TERRI SWALLOW

SENIOR WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPER

linkedin.com/in/terriannswallow

EXPERIENCE

TECHNICAL LEAD @ IVES GROUP, INC. PREV: SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER, INTERUM DIR. OF WEB DEV

Collection and SAAS reporting of US, Canadian and International public financial accounting data for analysis by private firms & educational institutions

2014 - PRESENT

- Build interfaces for data entry, quality control and analysis
- Introduced updated development practices and strategies to bring a large legacy code base up to date
- Involved in needs analysis for defining and scoping projects
- Mentoring junior developers and providing guidance on refactoring and modernizing coding standards

Technologies: PHP, MySQL, ¡Query, Bootstrap, Symfony, Composer

TECHNICAL LEAD FOR SCOUT.ME WEBSITE @ TELENAY, INC.

A publicly traded GPS company, providing driving directions through smartphone applications and OEM automotive equipment acquired goby, a location based things to do engine startup

2010 - 2014

- Developed a mobile friendly site to accompany the desktop version in reaction to analytic trends. Over the course of the following year the two sites were consolidate into a single responsive design with Backbone.js, as a rebranded, Scout.me
- Integrated ad server for both mobile app and web use
- Worked with various APIs and web services. From supporting a REST ISON API through the front end, communicating with the JAVA back end by XML to using 3rd party API's for both supplemental content and sponsored ad placements
- Worked with team through total rebranding of the web site after acquisition
- · Sprint planning, task prioritizing and release management responsibilities
- On call support contact for front end environments
- JS SDK integration to sync the website's content with existing Scout by Telenav GPS smartphone apps

Technologies: PHP, Memcache, Varnish, Apache, jQuery, OpenX, WordPress, API development & maintenance, VirtualBox, Jenkins, Grunt, Backbone. JS, SASS, Pingdom, Monit

PROFILE

I an Internet maker and creative problem solver. With over 10 years in the industry, I bring a variety of experiences building products online to any team. My past roles include projects and organizations of various sizes as well as diverse responsibilities and clients. I am interested in a role where I can be hands on in a code base with a strong creative team that stand by their product. My skills range the full stack with specialization in the areas of front and back end development.

SKILLS

FULL STACK DEVELOPMENT RANGE: NOVICE - EXPERT

Front-end

HTML, CSS, SEO, JS, JQUERY, VUE.JS

Back-end

PHP, MYSQL, VARNISH, MEMCACHE

COMPOSER, GRUNT, SASS, GIT, SCRUM NPM, MERCURIAL

Mobile

RESPONSIVE WEB, PHONEGAP

Sys Admin

JENKINS, SHELL, AWS, APACHE, NGINX

Design

UX. PHOTOSHOP, THEMES, TEMPLATES

TERRI SWALLOW

Page 2 of 2

EXPERIENCE (CONT)

WEB DEVELOPER @ CHITIKA INC.

Search targeted ad network

2008 - 2010

- Built UI's for internal and client earning reports
- Split testing for lead generation on landing pages and ad units to optimize ad performance network wide creating a 2 to 10% increase in CTR
- Built custom KPI reporting from OLAP server to display on monitors around the office to indicate uptime, revenue, traffic stats and trends for sales, marketing engineering and executive teams

Technologies: PHP, MySQL, WordPress customization and plugin development

WEB DEVELOPER @ MINDFIRE INTERACTIVE

Design agency

2007 - 2008

- Front and back end development for client projects including law firm lead generation, corporate intranet, professional training sites, banks and software startups
- Optimizing sites for search engines and direct marketing campaign tracking

Technologies: PHP, MySQL, ASP

WEB DEVELOPER @ BOB VILA.COM

The online home improvement and renovation community, how to, video and content resource to accompany the Bob Vila brand

2005 - 2007

- Custom feature development for sponsored content
- Developed content management tools for large scale content and article directory
- Updating existing site for improved SEO and web accessibility
- Built tools for community interaction and administration

Technologies: PHP, MySQL

EDUCATION

THE NEW ENGLAND INSTITUTE OF ART

BACHELOR'S OF SCIENCE - MAY 2006
Interactive Media Design & Development

CONTACT



Phone

774-249-2850



Email

terri.ann.s@gmail.com



Web

terriann.github.io

HOBBIES

Quilting / Cooking / Photography Kayaking / Blogging / Line Dancing Product Development / Marketing Social Media / Affiliate Marketing